Guide to the István Deák Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV. Habsburg Army Research Notes, undated
  - Subseries IV.2. Research Notes, undated
    - Research Notes--Habsburg Army Secondary Literature, D-F, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Research Notes--Habsburg Army Secondary Literature, G-L, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Research Notes--Habsburg Army Secondary Literature, M-O, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Research Notes--Habsburg Army Secondary Literature, O-R, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Research Notes--Sereinigg, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Research Notes--Habsburg Army Secondary Literature, S, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Research Notes--Habsburg Army Secondary Literature, Sz-Z, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Research Notes--Austrian Army in Italy-1859 undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Research Notes--The Nationality Question in the Habsburg Army, Regimental Histories, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Research Notes--Chapter III, Education, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Research Notes--Chapter V, from Pay Day to Pay Day, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Research Notes--Chapter VI, Latter Day Knights, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Research Notes--Pensions, Orphans and Widows, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Research Notes--Appendix I, Records, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Research Notes--Bibliography, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Research Notes--Salt Lake City, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Research Notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 20 to 21)
    - Research Notes--Austro-Hungarian Project, General Readings, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Research Notes--Austro-Hungarian Relations, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Research Notes--Questions about Hungarian Ancestors, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Research Notes--Noble Officers, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Research Notes--Army Organization, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
- Series V. Weimer Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Cause,1930-1970
  In 1969, Deak published his first book, Weimer Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes. The book was based on his dissertation, and this series contains the administrative files, research files, copies of the original documents used in his research as well as microfilm and correspondence.
  - Subseries V.1. Research Notes, 1962-1968
    The research notes for this book mostly contain copies of original documents used by Deak in writing the book. He was researching newspapers, documents, and pamphlets from the Weimer period, and kept photocopies and microfilm of many of the materials. The series also contains photographs used in the final version of the book.
    - Research Notes--photocopies from the Library of Congress, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Research Notes--photographs, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Weimar Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes-- Outlines, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Carl Von Ossietzky--Newspaper Articles, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Carl Von Ossietzky Articles--Interviews, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Weimar Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes--Notes 1968 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Research Notes--Collective Portrait Statistics, Weltbühne, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Microfilm (Box 18)
  - Subseries V.2. Die Weltbühne, 1930
    One of the most important documents that Deak used was the German journal Die Weltbühne. The major figure in his book was Carl von Ossietsky, a German radical and winner of the Nobel Peace Prize in 1935. Von Ossietsky was the publisher of Die Weltbuhne from 1927 until it was banned by the Nazis in 1933. Deak had original copies of the journal from November and May 1930 that he used in his research.
    - Die Weltbühne, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Subseries V.3. Administrative Files, 1963-1970
    This subseries contains the administrative files regarding the publication of the book. Deak corresponded frequently with the University of California Press on a variety of different issues. There were numerous reviews of the book during 1969 and 1970, as well as letters regarding review copies, corrections and critiques.
    - Weimar Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes Comments, Appraisals, Critiques, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Weimar Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes, Administrative Files, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Weimar Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes, Correspondence with University of California Press, 1964-1970 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Weimar Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes, Contract, Fliers, Announcements, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Weimar Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes, Chapter III, Notes, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Weimar Germany's Left Wing Intellectuals, A Political History of the Weltbühne and its Causes, Notes I, Collaborators, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 7)